René Char Papers, 1929-2007 (bulk 1939-1980): Finding Aid C1599
Manuscripts Division
- Papers on the French Resistance, 1939-1980; 1929-2007; 11 boxes
  - Resistance V, 1929 July 6-1976; 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1929 July 6-1962; 1 box
      - Miscellaneous Letters, 1944; 1 folder (Box B-001238, Folder 18)
        Includes letters from Capitaine A. Beyler, Christiane Van Hoof, Madame Veillet (with a photo negative) regarding the whereabouts of her son Roger Veillet, and Lieutenant Albert Lebuy, among others.
      - Miscellaneous Letters, 1945; 1 folder (Box B-001238, Folder 19)
        Includes letters from Daniel Turberville, E. Broïda, "Jacques," Raoul Marchais, Jane Peyrefitte, Polyte, Captain Mourier, C. Jenin, Lieutentant Beaurain Charles, Yves Thomas, and others.
      - Miscellaneous Letters, 1946-1948; 1 folder (Box B-001238, Folder 20)
        Includes letters from G. Alamano, Bayard, Colonel Roman-Petit, Gérard, and others.
      - Miscellaneous Letters, 1950-1962; 1 folder (Box B-001238, Folder 21)
        Includes letters from Emile Etienne, Colonel Péri, Colonel Bernard, Lucie Fradisse, Captain Roger, and others.
      - Miscellaneous Letters, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001238, Folder 22)
    - General A. Azan, 1945-1949; 1 folder (Box B-001238, Folder 23)
    - Pierre Michele, Alias Camille Rayon, 1945-1954; 1 folder (Box B-001238, Folder 24)
      Includes numerous letters from Pierre Michelle under the alias Rayon, as well as one letter from A. Crassous and one from Courcon to Char regarding Michelle, and a confidential document.
    - Speech on the Death of Florent Piquet, 1976; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 1)
    - Roger Brielle, 1945-1956; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 2)
  - [Resistance VI], 1939-2008; 2 boxes
    Consists of materials related to Char's service with the 173e RA (Régiment d'Artillerie) in Alsace as well as those related to his close friends in Céreste, including Marcelle Pons and her daughter Mireille Sidoine, and Georges Roux. Also included are items concerning the death of Roger Bonon killed in Dunkirk in May 1940.
    - 173rd R.A.L.G.P.A., 1939 November 19-1982 September 15; 1 box
      - B.O.E.M. Booklet, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 15)
        Includes Char's signature on the back cover.
      - Letter from Char to Artillery Colonel in Nîmes, 1940 November 12; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 16)
        Asks to be a reserve officer.
      - Letter from Colonel Chomette, 1939 November 19; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 17)
      - Letter from Char to Colonel Chomette, 1940 January 25; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 18)
      - Bariadnisky, Madeleine, 1940 June 8; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 19)
      - Dantant, Georges, 1940-1969; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 20)
        10 letters.
      - Demobilization Document, 1940 July 21; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 21)
      - Pascal, Pierre, 1939 December 8; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 22)
      - Sicard, Jean, 1940-1945; 1 box
        33 letters.
        - Sicard, Jean, 1940-1941; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 23)
        - Sicard, Jean, 1941-1945; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 24)
      - Lapierre, Charles H., 1941 June 6; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 25)
      - Baudry, Robert, 1940; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 26)
      - Pascal, Pierre, 1947; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 27)
      - Royer, Chanoine, 1956; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 28)
      - Damgalongue, S., 1940 February 25; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 29)
      - Marc, Georges, 1982 September 15; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 30)
      - Fonjallaz, Anne, 1940-1942; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 31)
        4 letters to Char and his mother.
    - Marcelle Pons Sidoine and Her Daughter Mireille, Céreste, 1942-2008; 2 boxes
      - Maquis Emblem Drawing, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 32)
      - Photographs, 1943; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 33)
        Photographs depict Marcelle, Mireille, Char and others; originals and reproductions.
      - Note from Char to Marcelle, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 34)
        Written on a map of the Hautes-Alpes region in southeastern France.
      - René Char and Marcelle Correspondence, 1944-1949; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 35)
        Copies of letters.
      - Letter from Marcelle, 1948; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 36)
      - Certificate of Membership in SAP for Marcelle, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 37)
        Photocopy.
      - Letters from Char to Marcelle, 1946-1983; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 38)
        Copies
      - Letters from Char to Mireille, 1945-1983; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 1)
      - Letters and a Telegram from Mireille to Char, 1946-1948; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 2)
      - Text entitled "Le Devoir", 1942; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 3)
        Copy of the text.
      - Mairie Pons de Céreste Letter, 1946; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 4)
      - Letters during Hotel Montalembert Stay to Char, 1946-1947; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 5)
      - Letters from Mireille to Marie-Claude Char, 2007-2008; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 6)
    - Georges Roux, Céreste, 1956-2008; 1 box
      - Céreste Ceremony Plaque Text, Autograph Note, and Black and White Photographs, 1983; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 7)
      - Letter from Mireille Sidoine, 2008; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 8)
      - Georges Roux and Marie-Claude Char Correspondence, 1989-2007; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 9)
        Includes letters, postcards, as well as a short story written by Georges Roux.
      - Georges Roux and René Char Correspondence, 1969-1987; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 10)
      - Marie-Claude Char Letters, 2008; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 11)
      - René and Marie Pons Letters to René Char, 1956; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 12)
      - Letter from Florence Sidoine, Daughter of Marcelle, to René Char, 1983; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 13)
    - Death of Robert Bonnon, 1939-1941; 1 box
      killed in Dunkirk in May 1940
      - Photograph of Bonnon, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 14)
        Dedication on photograph states, "son compagnon de vie." Also includes a note.
      - Letters from Robert Bonnon to René Char, 1939-1940; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 15)
      - Letter from Commander Rozec to Bonon's Mother Concerning His Death, 1941; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 16)
      - Postcards to René Char from Robert Bonnon's Family, 1940-1941; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 17)
  - SAP Records, Service Documents Post Liberation, 1937-1970; 2 boxes
    Includes letters, memos, official documents, and personnel files.
    - Denis Rogstagne Letter, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 18)
    - Claude D. Letter, 1966; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 19)
    - Emile Bouvier Letter, 1950-1952; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 20)
    - Gabriel Cousier, 1937-1939; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 21)
    - Ramirez Letter, 1952; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 22)
    - Maxime Fisher Letter and Postcard, 1945-1949; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 23)
    - H. Dumay Letter, 1947; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 24)
    - Maurice Gonnet Letter, 1946; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 25)
    - General Cochet Letter, 1945; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 26)
    - Philippe Farine Letter, 1952; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 27)
    - Unidentified Letter, 1939; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 28)
    - Documents about the Death of Léa Piquet, 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 29)
    - General Azan Attestation Letter, 1950-1957; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 30)
    - Marie-Claude Char Note, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 31)
    - Carte de la Direction Technique des Services Spéciaux, 1944; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 32)
    - Attestation D'appartenance aux FFC, 1949; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 33)
    - Avis D'affectation du René Char, 1950-1951; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 34)
    - Letters from Les Premiers de la Résistance, 1946; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 35)
    - Demand D'attestation, 1949; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 36)
    - René Char Notes about Jean Roux's Resistance Activities, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 37)
    - Auguste Georges Castor Death Notice, 1952; 1 folder (Box B-001240, Folder 38)
    - Emile Etienne Attestation Letter, 1947-1950; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 1)
    - Cne Alexandre, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 2)
      30 documents relating to SAP, including OPS couriers, personnel lists, reports, letters, among other materials.
    - Section Atterrissage Parachutage (SAP) Documents, 1944; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 3)
      Includes personnel lists.
    - Hommes Matériel Parachutés, Rapports Divers, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 4)
      Contains various reports, letters, and documents about the parachute team.
    - Fiches Individuelles (Personnel Files) de la SAP, 1944; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 5)
      Contains 30 personnel records. One of these, that of Robert G. Cavagni, includes his black and white photo and a note attached to the back from Doctor Pierre Nalin.
    - États des Services, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 6)
      Contains various records and documents, including member files.
    - Renseignements Surveillance Messages René Char, 1944-1967; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 7)
      Contains military documents, mission orders, and letters.
    - Notes de Service, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 8)
      Includes: memos, attestations, military documents and letters, as well as personnel files, many of which include black and white photos and/or fingerprints.
  - Resistance Texts, 1939-2002; 2 boxes
    Includes letters, documents, and writings, including those by Edith Mora and Greta Rau as well as items that had been on exhibit.
    - Correspondence Relating to Simiane la Rotonde, 1945-1999; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 9)
      Consists of letters addressed to René Char and Marie-Claude Char from Marcel Loubiche, Edmé Carretier, Héloïs Castor, the mayor of Simiane concerning Auguste Castor and the death of five Royal Air Force airmen in Simiane la Rotonde.
    - Colonel Péri Letters to René Char, 1965-1990; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 10)
    - "Mémoire de la Seconde Guerre mondiale en Vaucluse", 2002; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 11)
      Documents about Char's papers.
    - Laurent Pascal, "Maquis Ventoux", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 12)
      typed journal
    - Telegram from "Pétufrancombat" to René Char, 1945; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 13)
    - Handwritten Note (René Char?), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 14)
    - Exhibition Materials, 1944-1946; 1 box
      - Jacques Gilet Letters, 1945-1946; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 15)
        3 letters and one card.
      - Feuillets d'Hypnos Fragment Addressed to Zyngermann, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 16)
      - Memo by Goebbels, 1944 January 4; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 17)
        Memo written by Goebbels, commander of the Wehrmachtabout the word Katastrophe. Includes inscription by René Char "Lisez bien, maquisards! Alexandre"
      - Letter from Maurice (Lieutenant Maigret), undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 18)
        Includes handwritten note by René Char regarding the importance and confidentiality of the letter.
      - Memo from Lieutenant Colonel, 1944 October 31; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 19)
      - List of Personnel, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 20)
      - Information Bulletin of the Provisional Government, 1944 August 21; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 21)
      - Coordinates of Parachuting Grounds, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 22)
      - Letter from René Char to his Commander, 1944 November 15; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 23)
      - Exhibit Labels, 1944; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 24)
    - Map of Hautes-Alpes with parachute locations marked, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 25)
    - Récits de Résistance, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 26)
      Includes 18 typewritten pages with corrections and 2 handwritten pages of notes.
    - Letter from René Char to Jacques Chartier, 1953 May 24; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 27)
    - "Place de René Char" by Edith Mora, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 28)
      typescript
    - "En Marge D'oevures Nouvelles de René Char" by Greta Rau, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 29)
      Typescript of article published in the Neue Zürcher Zeitung on February 24, 1957; includes typed autograph: "bad translation of German."
    - Preface to the German Edition of Poésies de Char by Albert Camus, 1958; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 30)
    - Draft Letter from René Char to Claude Arnoux, 1973 February 28; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 31)
    - René Char Letter to E. Naegeler, 1957 June 14; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 32)
      Letter from Char to E. Naegeler, former Minister, concerning Louis Laurens.
    - Letters by Char Concerning the Basses Alpes Affair, 1946 May 1; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 33)
      2 letters and a handwritten transcript with correction of an article by the Franc-Tireur on the affair the Low Alps.
    - René Char Correspondence with Jean-Paul Samson, 1955; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 34)
      Correspondence with Jean-Paul Samson, director of "Témoins" (August 1955). Includes 2 typewritten letters of Char, one of which was not sent; 2 autograph letters not sent from Char and an autograph letter from JPS.
    - René Char Correspondence with Marceau Seignon, 1977-1983; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 35)
    - Postcard from René Char to "Enrico", 1986 July 28; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 36)
    - Letters and Documents from General Cochet, 1948-1949; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 37)
      Concerning the Resistance Action Committee.
    - René Char Attestation of Assistance from Brauner to the Resistance, 1949 May 10; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 38)
    - Service Records, 1939-1944; 1 folder (Box B-001241, Folder 39)
    - Photocopies of Newspaper "Jeune Force", 1942; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 1)
    - Michal Launay Interview with Pierre Zyngerman, 1998; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 2)
  - Resistance 1940-1945, 1944-1988; 1 box
    - Important Staff Records, 1972-1976; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 3)
      Includes 1 card and 1 letter from Louis Coste, letters from the National Association of Veterans of the Resistance and Jean Garcin (13).
    - Résistance, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 4)
      Includes order of service of Captain Alexander to Gustave Roux, report of an incident of November 23, 1944; handwritten note addressed to Captain Alexandre; state of service of Lieutenant Signoret; telegram signed Cne Alexandre, declaration of Joseph Anfosso concerning the denunciation of Pierre Perissol.
    - Parachutages, Contre-Parachutages, 1944 November; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 5)
      Includes survey of land coordinates; land; list of names and registration numbers.
    - Résistance, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 6)
      Includes 1 handwritten note, lists of personnel for the Low Alps, land coordinates, request for reinstatement of second Lieutenant Deutsch signed Captain Alexandre, list of the General Staff of General de Gaulle, order of General Azan's mission, report of the situation of the units of the SAP, letter of André Turrel to the captain Alexandre, list of grounds and number of men assigned to each one, note of service of the Forces Françaises Combatants (FFC) of 9/21/44
    - Names and Registration Numbers, 1944; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 7)
    - Provisional Identity Certificates, 1944-1978; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 8)
      Certificates registered and signed. Includes 2 letters from Jacques Sirand to Char; summary of investigations by the FFC, 6 duplicate fact sheets; maintenance report of 14/11/44; and "Terrier case" memo.
    - Maxime Fisher Letter, 1986 November 28; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 9)
    - Pierre Bonvalet Letters, 1986; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 10)
    - Jean Garcin Letters, 1986-1988; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 11)
    - Transcript of Notebook of Charles Ferrenq, Alias Aramis, 1944; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 12)
  - Seuls Demeurent, 1945-1956; 1 box
    Correspondence relating to Seuls Demeurent.
    - Blanchard, 1946 May-June; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 3)
    - Brielle, Roger, 1945-1956; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 4)
    - Captain Beyler, 1945 August 25; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 5)
    - Marcenac, Jean, 1945; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 6)
      Letter includes header of the newspaper "le Patriote."
    - Alquié, Ferdinand, 1945 May 21; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 7)
    - Audisio, Gabriel, 1945 May 26; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 8)
    - Tavernier, René, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 9)
    - Jean Sicard "Serge", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 10)
      Letter about sending the "Pulverized" poem
    - Conseil Général de la Seine, 1946 June 28; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 11)
    - Monnerot, Jules, 1945-1946; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 12)
    - Sorbonne Faculty Member, 1946 June 30; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 13)
    - General Cochet, 1945-1947; 1 folder (Box B-001239, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Records, and Manuscripts, 1940-1993; 2 boxes
    Includes letters, official records and documents, addresses and speeches, and printed material, among other items.
    - A. Dumay Letters and Photograph, 1947; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 13)
      Includes 2 letters and a photograph.
    - Armand, Emile, 1974 January 12; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 1)
    - Assorted Letters to Char, 1940-1961; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 20)
      Includes letters from Colonel Peri, Marcelle, Choughi, Maxime Fisher, Andre Waldstein, Jean Ribaille.
    - Avon, Roger, 1948; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 32)
    - Bardouin, 1950; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 2)
      Letter to René Char.
    - Bernard (Lieutenant Colonel), 1964 December; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 3)
      One letter to René Char.
    - Bourgeois, Fernand and Cestamiere, Jeannot, 1949-1950; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 4)
      A letter and a postcard to René Char.
    - Bouvier, Emile, 1946-1956; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 5)
      Four letters to René Char.
    - Cabot, Andred, 1979-1980; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 6)
      Correspondence with René Char, and Char's attestation.
    - Castor, H., 1945; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 7)
      Letter to Captain Alexander (René Char).
    - Chaumien, Jean Supiron and Catherine, 1976-1980; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 8)
      Letter concerning Chaumien (Jean Supiron) and letter from Catherine Chaumien to René Char.
    - Decision No. 777, 1940-1944; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 18)
      Includes a document "Izon la Bruisse," dated February 22, 1944, by J.P. Maugard alias "Marchal" and a letter from the Special Commissioner requesting information on Char, dated September 21, 1940.
    - Exhibition Materials, 1940-1959; 1 box
      Includes some of the items that were exhibited in spring 2018 not identified elsewhere in the inventory provided by Marie-Claude Char.
      - List of Undesirables in Isle-sur-la-Sorgue, 1943 April; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 25)
      - René Char Membership Cards, 1945-1959; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 26)
        La France combattante, Section atterrissage Parachutage France R2, Sanatorium de la France combattante, SAP
      - Gestapo Archives File on Char, 1944-1945; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 27)
      - Emile Cavagni SAP Personnel File, 1944 June 8; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 28)
      - Special Commissioner of Avignon Letter to the Police Commissioner of Isle-sur-la-Sorgue, 1940 September 21; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 29)
      - Cabinet of the Prefect of Vaucluse Letter to to the Special Commissioner for Investigation, 1941 February 7; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 30)
      - Confidential Letters Concerning René Char, 1940; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 31)
        Photocopies of letters between the Prefect of Vaucluse, the Special Commissioner, the Police Commissioner and others concerning René Char, among others.
    - General Cochet, "Appel aux Résistants et à leurs Amis", undated; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 9)
    - Hand-drawn Illustration and Map, 1944 July; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 21)
    - Information Bulletin from the French Provisional Government, 1944 August 25; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 22)
    - Lea Piquet, 1970; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 14)
      Includes "Homage to Lea Piquet" by Char.
    - Les Differents avec le Regional SAP, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 15)
    - List of TV and Radio Programs About René Char, undated; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 24)
      Some note air dates.
    - Martin, Jean, de Reillanne, 1948 October 26; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 35)
    - Michel, Pierre, 1944 May; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 11)
      Two letters to Captain Alexandre (René Char).
    - Official Documents, Records, and Correspondence, 1944-1948; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 16)
      Includes Safety Questionnaire, memos from Cochet, death register extract, letters from the State Secretary of the Armed Forces, letter from Prisoners of War Department, and René Char correspondence with Pierre Michel.
    - Official Correspondence, Documents, and Clippings, 1944-1953; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 17)
      Includes letters and documents honoring Char, his attestation, a letter from Yves Farge, information bulletins from the French Provisional Government (1944), and newspaper clippings of articles about Char, among other items.
    - Péri, H., Colonel, 1963-1967; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 12)
      Three letters to René Char.
    - Plagne (Chef d'escadron), 1946 January 28; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 13)
    - Renaud de Jouvenel, 1951 November 8; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 14)
      RSVP
    - René Char Letter to Michelle Michel, 1980 February 11; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 19)
      Letter to Michelle Michel, curator of the Musée de l'Ordre de la Libération, includes a list of documents sent by René Char for exhibition.
    - Ribaille, Jean, 1947-1955; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 15)
      3 letters to René Char.
    - Rostagne, Denis, 1950-1959; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 16)
      Two letters to René Char.
    - Rouit, Eugene, 1955 May 26; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 17)
      Letter concerning Eugene Rouit.
    - Rousseaux, André, 1955 May 14; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 33)
    - Royer, Raymond, 1950-1953; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 18)
      One letter from Royer and two concerning Royer to René Char.
    - Speech Commemorating François Cuzin, 1969 July 12; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 10)
      Speech commemorating François Cuzin, killed July 1944.
    - Testanière, Jean (Jeannot), 1949; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 20)
    - Ytier, Robert, 1974 December 30; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 34)
    - Zyngerman, Pierre, 1967-1993; 1 folder (Box B-001243, Folder 19)
      Six letters to René Char and a 1993 interview with Zygnerman.
    - Zyngerman Interview, 1951-1967; 1 folder (Box B-001242, Folder 23)
      Includes a 1951 letter to René Char, 2 1951 postcards, and the 1967 Interview with Zyngerman
  - Marie-Claude Char, 1994-2003; 2 boxes
    Includes correspondence, clippings, photographs, and documents relating to anniversary and commemoration events, in particular the 50th anniversary of the death of five Royal Air Force airmen in Simiane la Rotonde organized by Char and former SAP members, François Delfini, Edmé Carretier, and Léon Michel.